alex lama noujaim

lamanoujaimagmail.com +44 7491 234027 Experienced product designer and developer, available for freelance work. I combine a technical background in engineering with subsequent training and work as a UX designer: my method involves carefully exploring the problem space to identify and quantify assumptions, followed by rapid prototyping and iteration to find the best solutions.

experience

Freelance Product Engineer

Jan 2019 - Present

- Covered the entire spectrum of research, design and development
- Built a bicycle sharing application with Vue.js and Firebase for an NGO
- Developed an audio plugin in C++ for a music production company

Product Designer, Simudyne

Mar 2017 - Jan 2019

- Led user experience and product design at Simudyne
- Designed and launched the simulation console, core to the product
- Transformed company brand, logo, typography, colours, and messaging
- Redesigned the website from scratch and part-implemented the design
- Designed simulation UIs for clients like The Bank of England and Barclays

Product & Strategy, Circadia

Mar 2016 - Dec 2016

- Conducted gorilla research to understand our market and inform product
- Drove a marketing strategy to grow social presence by 10 times
- Supported a successful application to the HAX accelerator in Shenzen
- Designed a sleep assistant app to monitor and improve sleep health

Design Lead, Shell Eco-Marathon

Sep 2014 - Jul 2015

- Led a team to design and build a novel hybrid fuel cell powertrain

- Designed, tested, and iterated each component until optimal

- Managed collaboration with other teams to build a race-certified vehicle

Research Asst., Imperial College

Jul 2014 - Sep 2014

- Tested performance of electrochemical devices using a self-built rig
- Worked with Dr. Billy Wu to vastly improve the efficiency of a fuel cell

education

MEng in Mechanical Engineering

Imperial College, 2012 - 2016

I specialised in mathematics, algorithms, design, statistics, and optimisation. Achieved within the top 10% of my year and was selected to study abroad for my masters. I wrote my thesis on simulation of post-surgery bone adaptation to maximise the life of jaw implants.

International Baccalaureate

King's College School, 2002 - 2012

Awarded an academic scholarship and achieved 13 A*s in my GCSE year. In sixth form I attained the maximum grade in my higher level subjects, Mathematics, Design, Physics, and Spanish, with an overall grade of 40/45.

skills

User Research, Data Visualisation, Journey
Mapping, Interaction Design, User Interface Design,
Scenarios, Copywriting, Persona Construction,
Interviewing, Surveys, Rapid Prototyping,
Competitive Analysis, Wireframing, Storyboarding,
User Flows, Branding, Sketch, Adobe CS, HTML,
CSS, Vue, Javascript, Firebase

other

I have played the piano for 20 years and competed in many regional music festivals, winning one and reaching the finals in others. As a photographer, I have shot for architectural magazines, music labels and my own personal projects. I speak fluent English, French, Spanish, Italian, and currently learning Arabic.